Good morning everyone and welcome back
to the briefing room. I should also say
hello from Ho Chi Min City, Vietnam.
Um, it's actually not morning for me.
It's uh 10:30 at night, but that's okay.
Excuse the setup, but I want to make
sure that I'm still bringing you the
show uh wherever I travel in the world.
Actually, the next uh episode is going
to be from Athens, Greece. Uh, I'm going
to go from here to Athens tomorrow, then
Athens to Cairo, Cairo to London, and
London back to uh to Washington. But
anyway, I'm in Vietnam for a couple of
reasons. Uh, the most important is to
give a speech to a group of a large
group of Australian investment bankers.
They hired me to come here and speak to
their annual convention. It was all
loads of fun. Uh, but I wanted to take
the opportunity of being here
to actually see Vietnam. And that's why
I'm here for a whole week.
I have four cousins, three of whom are
still alive, but with whom I'm very
close. And all four of them served in
Vietnam in combat positions. All four of
them returned from Vietnam with the
Bronze Star, two of them with the Purple
Heart, and all four of them with PTSD.
So, I wanted to get an idea of
what old Saigon, which is now Huchi Min
City, uh was like as best that I could.
Um, I want to show you a couple of of
pictures first. One of the first things
I did was just to walk around the city.
It looks more like Hong Kong than any
place else that I've ever been. This is
a normal typical evening. It's so hot
and so humid during the day that you
can't really you can't really do
anything. And so the whole place comes
to life in the evening and um everybody
that you talk to speaks English.
Everybody that you talk to wants to talk
about how much they love Bill Clinton
and Barack Obama because Bill Clinton
normalized relations, diplomatic
relations with Vietnam. And Barack Obama
um negotiated the uh Trans-Pacific
Partnership and opened free trade with
Vietnam and it changed the lives of
everybody in the country. That's not to
say that they have forgotten what the
war was like.
So I wanted to do several things. I
wanted to go into the jungle and I've
got some pictures of the jungle. Um, I'm
here with my brother-in-law and we hired
a guy to take us into the jungle. This
is about 2 hours southwest of Ho Chi Min
City, Saigon, in the jungle on the way
to the Mikong Delta. It really is thick
like this. Uh, go to the next slide and
I'll show you. Every once in a while
you'll come upon something like this. a
sign that says B-52 bomb crater and
they're deep 6 8 10 feet deep and the
jungle has sort of taken them back. Um,
one of the things that we did on that
first day that we were here, please go
to the next slide was something called
the Coochie tunnels.
The the Vietkong
dug 250
kilometers of tunnels. This tunnel has
been widened so tourists could get into
it. My I I'm not a fat guy, but my chest
was too big. I literally could not get
into the hole. Uh 250 kilometers. What
you do is you hold that up and then you
sink yourself down. I'm stuck. But it
just gives you an idea. Vietnamese are
small people and it's because they had
been uh malnourished for so many years.
And then these guys had to pull me out
because I I was stuck. Uh but anyway,
they were malnourished and um
as a result they're they're much much
smaller than the average American
soldier.
So they took advantage of that by
digging these tunnels, using the tunnels
to move weapons and ammunition. These
are the inside of some of the tunnels
and they go deep. Some of them are 3 m,
some are 6 m, and some are 20 m deep.
Um, the ventilation systems are
incredibly sophisticated. Uh, you don't
even know that these are ventilation
pipes because they're disguised as
termite mounds
or disguised as bamboo groves.
But anyway, it gives you an idea. 250
kilometers of this
Go ahead to the next one.
You see memorials, monuments
uh to the North Vietnamese fighters and
the Vietkong, the South Vietnamese uh
pro-communist fighters everywhere. Uh
this was just in a uh in a gift shop.
And these are some of the remnants of
bombs and rockets that were just found
right there in that immediate area. Uh
we also went to the presidential palace
which was fascinating. More interesting
was something called the war remnants
museum. Um it will make you sick to your
stomach and it will make you ashamed of
many of the things that we did during
the Vietnam War, especially in relation
to the use of Agent Orange. Um, it's an
incredible experience and really
something that I think every American
should see. With that said,
I have not met a Vietnamese who
even wanted to talk about this. To them,
it's in the past. They like the United
States. They like Americans. They want
us to be friends. This is all history.
They even told me, several people told
me that English now is now compulsory in
the school system.
So, every Vietnamese child speaks
English. It's really remarkable. Can we
go to the next one? We went down also
into the Mikong Delta. Uh this is one of
the literally thousands of canals
uh where where people live and where
much of the Vietnam War was fought. Um
it is grim. You can only imagine what it
was like 50 or 60 years ago. Uh, water
everywhere, bugs everywhere, snakes, and
I mean pythons and cobras and crocodiles
everywhere.
I I don't know how people live in these
mangrove swamps, but that's what they
were, mangrove swamps. I have a couple
of other pictures. Go to the next one,
please, just to give you an idea of what
it's like. And, you know, most of these
boats have goods on them. They're
transporting, you know, cases of
cigarettes or, you know, pots and pans
or passengers or whatever. This is just
how people get around in the Meong
Delta. Go ahead to the next one.
One of the most iconic photographs of
the 20th century is a picture that many
of you will know. It's a picture of
dozens of people on the roof of a
building. Many Americans think it was
the American embassy. It wasn't the
American embassy. It was um it was an
apartment building that was secretly the
CIA's station in Saigon.
There was a helicopter
sitting a top this little hut on the
roof of the building. People were
climbing that now bent ladder trying to
get on the last flight out of Saigon.
The picture won the Puliter Prize. Uh,
this is just a workingclass apartment
building now, but we bribed the the
security guard down on the first floor
and uh and he let us go up there and
take pictures. Crazy enough, there's an
abandoned bar up there that looks like
it was abandoned in 1975.
People just left it the way it was the
day the United States bugged out in
1975. It was an incredible thing to see.
I'm very grateful to this group of
Australian bankers for inviting me to
Vietnam. The speech was a lot of fun. I
always enjoy these speeches. I enjoy the
Q&A after. It gives me a chance to speak
frankly about what's going on in the
world much much in the way that we do
here on the show. Uh and then I went on
this um they had a dinner cruise on the
uh Saigon River
which was fun in and of itself, but what
I really enjoyed was being able to talk
about what's in the news. And I'll tell
you what, it's not just the Australians.
It's not just the Vietnamese. It's not
just the South Koreans. We stopped in
South Korea on the way over here.
Everybody is confused about American
foreign policy. They just simply don't
understand what we're doing. I was
talking to a Westerner a couple of days
ago and he said, you know, we want the
United States to succeed. We all do.
Because a successful United States is a
peaceful United States. and a peaceful
United States makes the rest of the
world happy. But these wars of choice,
like what we're fighting currently in
Iran, it just confuses people. They
don't understand what the endgame is.
And I think that they were less pleased
when I told them that there doesn't
appear to be an endgame.
The administration really believed that
Iran would collapse on top of itself.
Um, as soon as we started bombing it, we
killed the Illah, we took out most of
the cabinet, we took out almost the
entire military leadership, we took out
every uh nuclear scientist and all that
did was it drove the Iranian people
together. It didn't lead to collapse.
So, we're going to talk about that a
little bit today. Actually, we're going
to start with that. There there's a lot
of breaking news uh today coming out of
the Middle East and specifically out of
the Persian Gulf. The news cycle may
feel like it has slowed down a bit. It's
August after all, but the the war has
not. We're on the verge of something
that really is a new world order that
could shift the balance of power for
generations to come. Yes, for the United
States role in the Middle East, but
especially for our allies in the Persian
Gulf. And this weekend gave us perhaps
the clearest sign yet. For the first
time,
Iran is striking ships in the Strait of
Hormuz. And the United States is
basically
not retaliating. Check out this video.
This is a cargo ship currently on fire
in the Persian Gulf,
and the White House has decided not to
retaliate. Now, kudos to them for not
retaliating because that would have to
come with a counter retaliation and
then, you know, it just gets worse and
worse and worse. And at least right now,
it's not getting worse.
But you see the ship on fire in the
straight of Hormuz after it was shot by
an anti- uh anti-ship cruise missile
fired by the Iranians a few weeks ago.
that would have triggered another round
of strikes.
But instead, the Trump administration
appears to be moving in the opposite
direction. During a phone interview with
Axios, Trump said this quote, "We are
lowkeying it. We are only
semi-negotiating with them. We're just
watching Iran with its huge inflation
and the fact that they have no money,"
unquote.
He stressed that Iran is quote in very
bad shape unquote economically and has
no money to pay its troops. The US naval
blockade has exacerbated the Iranian
regime's economic crisis. He said
that may be true. It may not be true,
but the Iranians said they're not
negotiating at all. There there's not
like negotiations light. There are no
indirect negotiations. There are no
negotiations going on at all. I want you
to take a look at a clip uh of the
Iranian foreign minister.
Our negotiations with Oman are regarding
the determination of a new maritime
route in the straight of Hormuz. These
negotiations have progressed well. I can
say we are in the final stages and the
old existing routes will be replaced
with new ones. Specialists are currently
working on the maps. Of course, this
does not mean the opening of the
straight of Hormuz. This agreement may
take place, but the opening of the
straight of Hormuz is contingent upon
the fulfillment of a set of other
conditions which have in any case been
conveyed through intermediaries.
>> Okay, so that's the key. Yeah, there are
there are negotiations going on, not
with the United States. They're between
Iran and Oman. And when the foreign
minister said
when he mentioned the maps he quite
literally meant the maps of the straight
of Hormuz. Now the channel on the
Iranian side is deeper and any ship can
pass through there. The channel on the
Omani side is much more shallow and it's
very difficult for ships to pass through
there. It's also more narrow. So
everybody goes through the Iranian side.
Well, you'll recall in the last couple
of weeks the handful of ships that tried
to go through on the Omani side, the
Iranians rocketed and set on fire.
So, what we have here is a negotiation
that has nothing to do with the United
States, that has nothing to do with the
US or Israeli bombing of Iran. It has to
do with the maritime navigation of the
straight of Hormuz.
And all of this comes after the United
States backed away from its threats to
launch major attacks against Iranian
civilian infrastructure. Remember what
we said weeks ago. It is a war crime to
attack civilian infrastructure. Period.
It's black and white law. But we attack
civilian infrastructure anyway because
who's going to do something about it?
Well,
why have we backed away from these
threats? One likely factor is that
American allies in the Gulf have been
furious with Washington after Iran
retaliated to the last round of strikes
by striking civilian infrastructure in
Qatar and Bahrain.
The Iranian position is, well, if the
Americans are going to strike our
civilian infrastructure and nobody's
going to do anything about it, we're
going to strike the American allies
civilian infrastructure because there's
nothing that anybody can do about that.
That's when Washington threatened
escalation. Iran demonstrated then what
escalation would look like. They
attacked a a cargo ship and Washington
backed off. Again, I'm going to tell you
it's a good thing that Washington backed
off because retaliating would have
ramped things up and it would just get
worse and worse and worse and we still
don't have an exit strategy from this
conflict. Now, Iran is negotiating from
one of their greatest positions of
strength since the conflict began. Iran
has completely shifted its conditions
for reopening the straight of Hormuz. On
Saturday, the head of Iran's Supreme
National Security Council, Muhammad
Bagger Solgader, said in a statement
that in order for the strait to reopen,
he said the US must never threaten nor
insult Iran in any language. Okay, good
luck. Permanently end the war against
Iran and Iran's allies in Lebanon, Gaza,
Yemen, and Iraq. Well, good luck with
that, too. lift the naval blockade and
withdraw military forces from the
surroundings of Iran,
provide full compensation for war
damages, lifting all sanctions and the
release of all Iranian frozen funds. So
remember, the Trump administration has
said that Obama executed a horrible Iran
nuclear deal
because Obama transferred $1.7 billion
to Iran as part of a decades old legal
dispute over a failed 1979 military arms
purchase.
If if you don't recall, in the final
final days of the Shaw of Iran in 1979,
the Iranians tried to buy 1.7 billion
dollars of uh aircraft and air force
equipment.
As soon as they transferred the 1.7
billion to us, the sha was overthrown.
The Ayatollah took over and we just kept
the money. It's been frozen ever since.
So the Obama administration agreed to
give them back the 1.7 billion. Um,
Donald Trump has complained about that
since it happened, but now the Trump
administration is talking about
unfreezing
$25 billion in frozen Iranian assets
just to get this conflict to end.
Now, my own personal belief is that's
actually the right thing to do. He's
going to take all kinds of for it
from the Democrats who are going to use
this for partisan purposes,
but releasing the frozen Iranian funds
is the right thing to do. Lifting
sanctions against Iran is the right
thing to do. Listen, one of the lessons
that I learned here in Vietnam is
identical to a lesson that I learned
when I went to Cuba in 2022. If you want
to overthrow a government and replace it
with something that is pro-western, open
the first McDonald's
because everything else comes after
that. You can't turn your head without
saying here McDonald's, Starbucks,
Kentucky Fried Chicken, Pizza Hut,
everywhere you look. And everybody's
pro-American.
But well, they weren't pro-American when
we were shooting them and blowing them
up. Just like the Iranians aren't
pro-American right now, but let that
first McDonald's open. We'll see how
their tune changes. Same thing in Cuba.
If you wanted to overthrow the Castros
or if you want to overthrow the current
Cuban government, open McDonald's. Watch
the whole thing fall apart.
Perhaps the most significant sign of
Iranian strength.
Those were conditions for reopening the
straight of Hormuz
used to be
Iran's conditions for signing a nuclear
deal. You see what I mean? They've taken
the same conditions that they were using
for signing the nuclear deal and they
sort of transposed them into the terms
for reopening the straight of Hormuz.
It's it's smart and it puts the United
States in a difficult position.
So what happens if we agree to these
demands? It just kind of puts us back
where we started. And when the White
House tells you that it's using economic
warfare to pressure Iran, that might
sound smart, but they've just suppressed
protests back in January, killing 30,000
civilians, right? Do we really think
sanctions will be enough to to win this
war?
I don't. We've had sanctions on the
Iranians since November of 1979.
How many more sanctions could there
possibly be?
Especially sanctions powerful enough to
lead to the collapse of the Iranian
government. I don't know of any. If
there were such sanctions, we would have
imposed them already.
Well, the Trump administration appears
to believe what Benjamin Netanyahu and
other Iran hawks have argued for years.
put enough pressure on the Iranian
government, weaken the security
apparatus and eventually the Iranian
people will rise up and overthrow it.
Trump in his first speech announcing war
with Iran, his very first speech told
the Iranian people, "Rise up. Now is
your time." That was his quote. Well,
just a few weeks after the Iranian
police murdered 30,000 protesters,
the United States comes in in this sad
bid to to encourage more protests
and they actually decided to start
killing Iranian law enforcement.
Yeah, let me repeat that.
We jumped up and down when the Iranians
killed protesters.
Many estimates say it was 30,000. The
Israelis say it was 80,000.
Um, and we decided to start killing
Iranian law enforcement officers,
police, and domestic security. According
to Iran's president, the US has focused
not on just killing military officials,
but also on killing civilian law
enforcement because they believed it
would fuel greater protests if the
regime lost its police. Listen to this.
What this is is that that was President
Pzeski and the president of Iran uh
addressing the National Security Council
and he is confirming that
um attacks have taken place against
individual police officers. We're not
talking about bombing police stations.
That's not happening. We're talking
about assassins and saboturs on the
ground, likely Israelis, because the US
doesn't have a presence inside Iran, and
the Israelis brag about the extent of
their presence, and they are
assassinating individual policemen. Uh,
and what President Bizeskian said in
that clip is this is something that the
Americans and the Israelis did in
Afghanistan and in Iraq. It's it's part
of the arsenal of
operations that the US and Israel carry
out. And what's the result been? The
result has been that the Iranian people
are as unified as ever.
So instead of leading to the immediate
collapse of this country,
we have unified Iranians on the ground,
whether they were pro-regime or
anti-regime. I said in the in the
beginning of uh of this podcast series
that one of the most important lessons I
learned from the Iraq war when I was at
the CIA was that we are never seen as
liberators.
We're seen as attackers and occupiers.
I think the time is
beyond ready to end this thing.
There was another development in the
Middle East just over the last couple of
days that is incredibly important that
the American media
has largely ignored and that is
something called the Mecca Agreement.
This is footage from Islamabad,
Pakistan, from Turkey and from Saudi
Arabia this week as the three countries
celebrated a new trilateral security
agreement and they're calling it the
Mecca Agreement.
While Washington has been focused on
this Iran war, three of the most
powerful countries in the Muslim world
have just quietly created a completely
new security alliance.
So, we've got a little bit of video I
wanted to show you. This is in Mecca,
the holiest city in Islam. That's the
president of Pakistan. and he was joined
by President Erdogan right there of uh
of Turkey and Crown Prince Muhammad bin
Salman of Saudi Arabia. Uh they took the
opportunity to pray for the success of
the pact. The other leaders made the
minor pilgrimage called the Umrah. And
uh this is something that is going to
change the face of the region. And let
me explain why.
These are three of the most powerful and
important
countries in the entire Muslim world.
Pakistan is a nuclear power. It has
nuclear weapons and it has a bitter
mortal enemy in India. Saudi Arabia has
long sought nuclear weapons, actively
sought nuclear weapons since the 1980s.
And Dewey Clarage, a former deputy
director for operations at the CIA, who
has since passed away, just before his
death, gave an interview on MSNBC in
which he said that he believed the
Saudis already had a nuclear bomb, that
they had purchased it from the
Pakistanis.
Saudi Arabia's big enemy is Iran.
Turkey
is one of the most powerful and
important armies in NATO behind only the
United States and Germany.
And Turkeykey's big enemy is Israel.
So this is a mutual defense treaty,
meaning an attack on one is an attack on
all, just like article 5 of the NATO
charter. So the agreement means
different things for each one of these
countries. For Pakistan,
if Pakistan is is attacked by India,
Saudi Arabia and Turkey will come to its
aid. If Saudi Arabia is attacked by
Iran,
Turkey and Pakistan will come to its
aid. Two weeks ago, the Israeli defense
minister gave a speech in which he said
that Israel's next war will be against
Turkey. So let's let's play that out.
Let's say that there is a conflict
between Israel and Turkey. All Turkey
has to do as a member of NATO is to
invoke article 5 of the charter. An
attack on one is an attack on all. And
theoretically, the United States would
have to declare war on Israel. Well,
that's never going to happen in a
million years. It'll be the end of NATO.
But now nuclear armed Pakistan
and Saudi Arabia will come to
Turkeykey's assistance.
It really does change the face of the
region. And most importantly, it leaves
the United States completely out of it.
What if the way money works is about to
change? Not someday, not hypothetically,
but right now. China and the United
States are both making moves that
suggest we could be heading towards
something that the world hasn't seen in
over 50 years. A return to goldbacked
money or something very close to it.
China is shutting down paper gold
trading at four of its biggest banks
all in the same day. And they're
building a new system that settles in
physical gold instead. On our side, the
government is sitting on more than 8,000
tons of gold still valued at $42 an
ounce on the books. $42 an ounce.
Legislation to fix that has already been
introduced in Congress. If both
superpowers start anchoring their
currencies to gold, what happens to the
price? And more importantly, what
happens to every dollar in your
retirement that isn't backed by anything
at all? That's the question a free
report from American Alternative Assets
answers. It's called The Day Money
Changes Forever. And if you have an IRA
or a 401k, you need to read it right
now. Get your free copy at
johnlovesgold.com.
That's johnlovesgold.com
or call 888G053.
So according to a joint statement that
was released by the three governments
simultaneously, it says the Mecca joint
defense agreement is intended to
strengthen collective deterrence against
any act of aggression and stipulates
that an armed attack against any of the
three would be regarded as an attack on
all. That is essentially the principle
at the heart of NATO's article 5. The
Turkish vice president Chevdet Yamas
said the agreement was not aimed at any
specific country. That's true. A Turkish
official added that it was purely
defensive and did not abregate any
existing agreements that the countries
had with any other countries. Okay, but
let's think about what this means in
practice. As I said, it's Pakistan
versus India.
It's Turkey versus Israel.
and it's Saudi Arabia versus Iran and
the Houthis in Yemen.
Suddenly, these conflicts that were
largely bilateral have the potential to
become multilateral,
much bigger, involving countries with
nuclear weapons. If India and Pakistan
were to go to war again, an attack on
Pakistan would now theoretically be
treated as an attack on Saudi Arabia and
Turkey. If Israel and Turkey end up in a
military confrontation, Pakistan and
Saudi Arabia would jump in to support
Ankura. And don't forget that
Pakistan and Turkey now probably have to
join the Saudis in their fight against
the Houthis. And they don't sound
intimidated by this agreement at the
Houthies, that is. At least they're not
acting like they're intimidated. Take a
look at this this uh video clip.
Those
are Houthy surfaceto-air missiles.
Correction,
those are Houthy surfaceto-surface
missiles and they're being fired at
Saudi Arabia
and that's after the agreement was
signed.
They're not afraid, but they may become
afraid when the Turks send troops and
the Pakist Pakistanis send troops and
the the Yemen government that's
extraordinarily weak but recognized
internationally musters enough troops to
send. It's only going to get worse.
But listen to this. Israel is not at all
happy with this agreement. Check out
this video clip.
There are
Wow. First, that's what I want to say.
Uh, much of what he said is absolutely
true. There's one thing he said that's
not true. I'll get to in a minute. But
the Israelis are genuinely worried about
this. I mean, he just said, "We have a
frontal," he called it an assessment, a
frontal assessment with Turkey. Meaning
the Israelis are prepared to fight the
Turks. Even though Turkey is what, 12
times the size and population, or not
the size, it's many, many times the
size. It's 12 times the population of
Israel. The Israelis were ready to go at
it with the Turks, knowing that the
Americans are going to protect them from
the Turks.
But the Americans can't protect them
from the Pakistanis or even from the
Saudis for that matter.
So this is something that the Israelis
did not expect. I can guarantee you it's
something that the Americans didn't
expect, but it's something that makes
the Turks, the Saudis, and the
Pakistanis very, very happy. Now, he
made another point, too, that Israel is
going to have to deepen its relationship
with Greece, Cyprus, the United Arab
Emirates, and Somaliand.
Somali land is not a real country. It's
the northernmost state in Somalia. It is
recognized only by Israel, not by any
other country in the world. The reason
being is that you can practically swim
from Somali land to Yemen. And the
Somali landers are going to give the
Israelis an air force base in exchange
for this diplomatic uh recognition.
Kudos to the Israelis. It was a smart
move.
But
better relations with, you know, Greece,
Cyprus, Somali land, even the Emirates,
it's not going to cure anything. The the
Saudis and the Emiratis are they're kind
of involved in a little bit of a
democratic uh diplomatic kurfuffle right
now. Um, that's going to pass. They're
on different sides in Yemen. That's
going to pass.
um they're not terribly fond of each
other, but they live in the same
neighborhood. And so the Amiradis are
not going to choose the Israelis over
the Saudis. That's a pipe dream. Now,
one of the things that he said in that
clip is just not true. He said that the
Saudis were
uh on the on the verge of signing on to
the Abraham Accords. That is absolutely
not true. The Saudis have never been on
the verge of signing the Abraham
Accords. The White House will tell you
that they are and the Israeli media and
government will tell you that they are.
They're not. The Saudi position
on recognizing Israel has been
absolutely consistent since 1977.
We invited, [clears throat] President
Jimmy Carter invited the Saudis to Camp
David to negotiate the peace treaty with
the Israelis and the Egyptians. And the
Saudis demired, "No, thank you."
Remember, Saudi Arabia is not just your
run run-of-the-mill country, not your
just normal average Muslim country. The
king of Saudi Arabia is the custodian of
the two holy mosques. His title is not
just king. It's king and custodian of
the two holy mosques.
that carries with it incredible weight
not just in the Middle East but
excuse me but in every Muslim country in
the world.
Opening relations with Israel
and not getting a free and independent
and secure Palestinian state in the deal
is not going to happen ever. So the the
Saudis were never on the verge or on the
wall or on the fence about the Abraham
Accords. They were clear about it. We
will not sign the Abraham Accords until
there's a Palestinian state. Period.
That's the end of that.
A couple of people have asked me, "If I
were in a CIA briefing
for the United States,
what kind of questions would I ask
about this this new defense pact?"
Well, I' I've thought about this and
frankly my questions would be questions
that I would pose to the Secretary of
State or to the National Security
Adviser were he not the same person in
Marco Rubio. And my question would be,
what are you going to do?
I mean,
this administration has never really
supported NATO. They say NATO is
outdated and unnecessary. Is it? Is this
the beginning of the end for NATO? Do
the Turks also believe that it's the end
for NATO?
And if the answer is yes, what does this
mean for a European Unionwide defense
pact? Remember just 3 weeks ago
all of the defense ministers of the
European Union, which does not include
Turkey or the UK or the US or Canada,
met to discuss an EUwide
defense pact. And it's because they just
don't trust the United States to be
there if they need the help.
The world is changing quickly and uh and
we've got a front row seat.
If I were in a foreign intelligence
service for each of these countries, how
would I feel right now? Incredibly
optimistic.
It's funny to me that the United States
seems to be the country that is the
slowest to recognize that we have
already transitioned into a multipolar
world. The United States is not the only
great superpower anymore. We're not. We
can't win wars. We were in Iraq for 20
years, we lost. We were in Afghanistan
for 20 years, we lost. We attack Iran,
we're losing.
I mean, we're not talking here about
sending some planes in and capturing
Nicholas Maduro. These are honest God
wars, and we can't win them.
The Russians are in Ukraine. There's
almost nothing we can do about it.
Meanwhile, the Chinese are buying
friends all over the world with the Belt
and Road initiative.
So, if I were a foreign intelligence
service director, I would be very
pleased
with the way the these things are going.
I will add one thing. From the time of
my own service in Pakistan,
the Pakistanis don't love anybody as
much as they love the Saudis. They loved
the Saudis so much that they named one
of the biggest cities in the country
Fiselabad after King Fisel of Saudi
Arabia because he was so kind and so
generous to Pakistan. There are hundreds
of thousands
maybe more of Pakistanis in Saudi Arabia
working at all levels of the economy.
The military relationship between the
two countries was already rock solid as
is the intelligence sharing
relationship.
So this alliance is a natural move for
both the Saudis and the Pakistanis
including the Turks kind of surprised me
a little. And I I'm going to go on a
limb and say that a year ago, nobody
probably would have even thought about
inviting the Turks until Israel
threatened them.
The Turks don't think that the United
States or even the rest of NATO is going
to come to to Turkeykey's aid if Israel
were to attack. And so it sought out new
relationships, new alliances, and it
formed that alliance this week in Mecca.
I think that's where we're going.
Back to the conflict which really
sparked the entire current situation
that we're in in the Middle East. The US
proposed a 15point peace plan for the
Israel Gaza conflict. The most important
condition included the withdrawal from
Gaza of Israeli forces coupled with the
disarmament of Hamas.
Here is Benjamin Netanyahu's response.
And for those of you listening, I'll
summarize the translation uh from his
Hebrew on the other side.
You
is
committee.
foreign.
Is
call
Philadelphia.
I tell you what, you can't be any more
clear than that. There will not be a
Palestine, period, ever in any form on
any land.
He couldn't have been any more clear. He
doesn't care what Donald Trump says. He
doesn't care what Marco Rubio says. Or
he doesn't care what any American
politician says. There will not be an
independent Palestine.
I mean, what what more is there to say?
He also said that Israel will not stop
in Gaza until Hamas is disarmed. What
does that mean?
Well, the Israeli government considers
every man, woman, and child of any age
to be a combatant. And so, the war will
continue. The killing of civilians will
continue. The Israeli occupation will
continue. And if the United States
raises an objection, we're going to get
the middle finger.
It's as simple as that. Nothing's going
to change. 15-point plan. It can be a
onepoint plan or a 5,000point plan. He
doesn't care.
So, there's really nothing to look
forward to there. And and here's what
the White House had to say. This was so
interesting. This is one of the reasons
why I love politics so much. A senior US
official told Axios that the White House
quote is not bothered unquote by
Netanyahu's statement on the Gaza plan
and sees it as part of the election
season in Israel. Remember, there are
elections coming in November.
This spokesman said or senior US
official said, quote, "We understand
BB's political needs. We have no problem
with it as long as he continues to do
what we ask, especially regarding
restraining attacks in Gaza."
Really impossible to believe anyone in
their public statements. Everybody's
lying in every country. But one thing is
for sure. If the White House is willing
to give this much difference to Israel
because it's an election season there,
which is not a reason to be allowed to
commit war crimes,
then the situation in Gaza is not
getting any better anytime soon. Here's
something you don't see every day. A
chance to win an almost $600 bundle of
premium preparedness gear. Look, a more
self-reliant America is built by people
like you and me. It starts with people
who take responsibility, make a plan,
and prepare before we're tested. That's
the idea behind My Patriot Supplies Road
to preparedness challenge. It's bringing
together Americans who believe strong
families should be independent, capable,
and ready. Visit prepare likejkbr.com
to enter to win and become part of the
mission. Every participant has a chance
to win a family of four starter pack
covering food, water, power, and heat.
It includes a oneweek food supply for
four people, personal water filters,
solar rechargeable backup power, and
offgrid cooking essentials. That's a
lot. Enter the challenge at prepare
likejkbr.com.
One family receives the prize, but every
participant strengthens the mission.
This is your chance to be independent.
Be prepared. Be ready. Join the road to
preparedness challenge now at prepare
like jkbr.com.
So, folks, I I wanted to thank you again
for your reactions to so many of my
[laughter]
of my podcasts and interviews. I get I
get a real kick out of them. I really
do. There were a couple things that I I
thought deserved an explanation. We've
we've got two clips. Can we run that
first one?
>> So, he comes up to the eighth floor and
we go into the stairwell and I said,
"Let's go up to the roof." He's like,
"What?" I said, "Let's go up to the
roof.
He goes, "I I don't think I want to go
up to the roof." I said, "Yeah, come on.
Let's go." He said, "I'm uncomfortable
going up to the roof." And I said,
"Why?"
>> "You think I'm going to throw you off
the roof?
>> Come on, let's go. We'll talk up there.
>> It's a nice day."
>> He goes, "I don't want to go to the
roof." I said,
>> "Get up on theinging roof."
>> Yeah, I did.
I wasn't going to throw him off the
roof. I wanted him to think I was going
to throw him off the roof. But as
background,
in 2001, a friend of mine who was a
station chief in the Middle East called
me. I had been evacuated from Athens for
my own safety. And um he called me and
said, "What are you doing?" And I said,
"Nothing. They got me doing this job
training Middle Eastern intelligence
services,
but I'm bored."
I said, "What do you need? what do you
have going on? And he said, we've
recruited a double agent out here and
it's too dangerous for me to meet with
him. He said, the guy's insisting on
meeting only with the chief. Can you fly
out here every month and pretend to be
me? I said, absolutely. Well, the guy
was a double agent for one of our
gravest enemies in the world. And um
and so he didn't know that I knew that
he was a double agent. But every time we
would meet, he would immediately go to
this enemy country's embassy and report
back on our meeting.
Finally, this country
ordered him to kill me in our final
meeting. And headquarters freaked out
and I was like, "Relax." I said, "The
guy's afraid of his own shadow. He's not
going to kill me. He should be worried
that I'm going to kill him, frankly.
But we came up with a plan. And uh I
don't know. I just I kind of wanted to
scare him a little bit. And and um I
took him into the stairwell and told him
to get up on the roof. We're going to do
the meeting, not in in a hotel room.
We're going to do it on the roof of the
hotel. And he was genuinely petrified.
And finally, I laughed and I said,
"What's the matter with you? I thought
we were friends. I'm just pulling your
leg. You don't really think I'm going to
throw you off the roof.
He started crying.
Anyway, to make a long story short, one
thing led to the other to the other.
And he's been in prison since the spring
of 2001, and he's going to die there.
I think we have one more, too. One more
clip. Let's go to that. It's after the
cop warned me about people coming into
my room. unannounced. These two guys
just walk in boldly just walk in. I jump
up. I put my fist up. I go, "What do you
want?" One of them has a swastika on his
neck. It took up his entire neck. It
came up onto his face. The other one had
you tattooed on his eyelids. So I go,
"What do you want?" And and the the
swastika guy says, "You the new guy?" I
said, "Yeah, so." And he says, "You a" I
said, "No, I'm not a He said, "You a
rat?" I said, "No, I didn't have anybody
else in my case. I'm not a rat." He
says, "You a cho?" I go, "I don't know
what that word [music] means." He goes,
"Chomo, child molester." I said, "No,
I'm not a child molester." And he goes,
"Okay, you could sit with the Aryans in
the cafeteria." [music]
And I was like, "Oh,
I guess I'm with the Aryans now.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> That was not just my first day in
prison. That was my first hour in prison
when two Nazis, neo-Nazis, came into my
cell to ask if I was
gay, the f-word. And I said, "No, I was
not a an F-word.
Was I a rat? No. Was I a child
molester?" "No." "Then you can sit with
the Aryans." I sat with them for a
while, but then the Italians, the
Italians named Banano, Gambino,
Genevese, Lucesi,
etc.
um asked me why why I was sitting with
the Nazis in the cafeteria. I said, "I
don't know. My first day here, they told
me sit with them." And
one of the under bosses of one of the
five families very cinematically said,
"From today, you're with the Italians."
And so after that, I was with the
Italians.
That was actually at a podcast, not at a
bar. That was all superimposed. But ah,
you know, I have a sense of humor, too.
I got a kick out of it.
Folks, I wanted to say one other thing.
We have grown so dramatically
in this podcast. We've been doing it for
three weeks and we have 237,000
subscribers and I want to say thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. We can only
continue to do this because of you.
Thank you for your support. Thank you
for for letting us know that you
appreciate our take on the news. We
quite literally could not do it without
you and I really thank you from the
bottom of my heart. In the meantime,
we'll talk to you again in a couple of
days. If you haven't checked out my
other podcast, it's on Apple Podcast and
Spotify. It's called John Kuryaku's
Deadrop. I'm also on X and Facebook and
LinkedIn and Cameo and Substack, so you
can find a whole bunch of stuff there.
Thanks again. We'll see you in a couple
of